## MARVIN BRERETON

#### JUNIOR DEVELOPER

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### JUNIPER EDUCATION

**Junior Developer** 

January 2021 – Current

Juniper Education is a provider of world-class pupil tracking software, training and professional services to the education sector and is trusted by over 12,000 schools.

#### Responsibilities:

- Documented technical workflows and knowledge in private wiki for education of newly hired employees.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Designed and maintained streamlined, reusable and reliable code.
- Design tasks at start of sprint to estimate work amount and work on tasks in an orderly manner.
- Review pull requests and provide feedback.
- Present work to shareholders in sprint reviews.
- Investigate SPIKE tasks to create future work at request from product owner.
- Fixing bugs and perfecting SQL queries.
- Tech used: C#, SQL, Azure, Teams, Rider, Visual Studio, Git, PluralSight

#### SISRA LTD

**Junior Developer** 

#### February 2020 – December 2020

SISRA is a company that has provided web-based solutions to the education sector for over 10 years. SISRA is one of the market leaders with over 1,700 education providers and 130,000 users both in the UK and abroad.

#### Responsibilities:

- Documented technical workflows and knowledge in private wiki for education of newly hired employees.
- Designed and maintained streamlined, reusable and reliable code.
- Review pull requests and provide feedback.
- Present work to shareholders in sprint reviews.
- Investigate SPIKE tasks to create future work at request from product owner.
- Work with the whole team to understand and integrate business functionality into functional code.
- Fixing bugs and perfecting SQL queries.
- Tech used: C#, SQL, Teams, Visual Studio

Address: 4 Henderson Close, Upton, CH49 4QH

Contact: 07851 177 788

Email: Marvin.brereton@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/marvin-brereton

## MARVIN BRERETON

#### JUNIOR DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

Motivated, hardworking junior software developer with knowledge of C#, .NET, Azure and SQL languages, experienced in implementing new features, fixing bugs and team communication with 2 years of experience in software development within an educational company. I have a passion for creating semantic, clean code and have experience in working towards goals and have worked with multiple IDE's. I am keen to continue developing my skills and experience with the latest innovative development tools and procedures.

## **Education & Training**

Originally, I worked in hospitality with a long-standing dream to work as a software developer, I set out to learn from Udemy and WeSchools and created my first CV site. I started at SISRA in February 2020 and have been allocated training times during my development there and at Juniper Education as well as working alongside the development team.

### **Technical & Software Skills**

C# | SQL | Agile | .NET Framework | DevOps | Version Control (git) | MVC | Razor | Rider Visual Studio | SQL Management Studio | Exposure to HTML, CSS, Razor & JavaScript | Code Reviews | Debugging & Error Monitoring

## **Key Achievements**

- Receiving Kudos from a product owner for work on the project
- Participating in sprint reviews and delivering work completed details to shareholders
- GitHub Artic Code Vault Contributor Feb 2020

## **Personal Development**

In my spare time I make projects for myself to further my knowledge of code. My top 3 projects are:

Bug Tracker - January 2022 to current

Working on a bug tracker UI with account linking.

Portfolio Site – November 2019 to December 2019

I created a portfolio site with some basic projects.

CSS Styles Framework – July 2021 to August 2021

I created a CSS Styles framework to use in ongoing projects.

#### References

Address: 4 Henderson Close, Upton, CH49 4QH

Contact: 07851 177 788

Email: Marvin.brereton@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/marvin-brereton

# MARVIN BRERETON JUNIOR DEVELOPER

References available upon request

Address: 4 Henderson Close, Upton, CH49 4QH

Contact: 07851 177 788

Email: Marvin.brereton@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/marvin-brereton